marketindex.com.au 2019-06-04

# Privacy Policy - Market Index

## **SHORT**

No personally identifiable information is collected from visitors unless the visitor takes manual action to ensure it occurs (e.g. sends us an email, comments on a post, signs up to a mailing list, interacts with us via Social Media etc.).

Market Index doesn't sell a product or service so we only use the information you provide for correspondence purposes. All emails contain an "Unsubscribe" button.

Market Index use analytics (e.g. Google Analytics) to improve the website experience. These involve “cookies” to passively collect anonymous statistics (e.g. pages visited, browser used etc.).

## **FULL**

This following document sets forth the Privacy Policy for Market Index Pty Ltd acting as trustee for the Market Index Trust which publishes the website [www.marketindex.com.au](http://www.marketindex.com.au/).

Market Index is committed to providing you with the best possible customer service experience. Market Index is bound by the Privacy Act 1988 (Crh), which sets out a number of principles concerning the privacy of individuals.

**Collection of your personal information**  
There are many aspects of the site which can be viewed without providing personal information, however, there are circumstances where you may optionally provide personally identifiable information. For example, if you contact the Webmaster you will be submitting personally identifiable information (your email and any content contained within). Submiting a comment on a post, joining a mailing list or using social media can also involve personally identifiable information. We will never rent, share or sell any of your personally identifiable information.

As Market Index doesn't sell a product or service (we are an information website), we only use the information you provide for correspondence purposes. I.e. responding to your email, sending emails you have subscribed to, social media comments and blog post notifications.

The only people that have access to your email are Market Index staff and our third-party email provider. We will remove your email address from our database immediately upon request, or you can click the “Unsubscribe” button located at the bottom of every email. Contact us if you have any questions.

**Anonymous User Data**  
For each visitor to reach the site, we expressively collect the following non-personally identifiable information, including but not limited to browser type, version and language, operating system, pages viewed while browsing the Site, page access times and referring website address. This collected information is used solely internally for the purpose of gauging visitor traffic, trends and delivering personalised content to you while you are at this website. From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will use for these new purposes only, data collected from the time of the policy change forward will adhere to our updated practices.

**Google Analytics & Advertising**  
We use Google Analytics and may use other types of analytics software to improve the experience for website visitors. Google Analytics uses "cookies" to passively collect traffic data and better understand how visitors interact with a website. Don’t worry, we have no idea who you are. Analytics data is complied anonymously by Google, and Google tell us awesome things like what devices people are using to access the website (e.g. iPhone or Desktop), what browsers are being used (e.g. Internet Explorer or Safari) and what pages people visit on the website. These anonymous statistics are then used by Market Index staff to optimise the website for a better user experience.

Google [DoubleClick](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DoubleClick) software is used to serve the advertisements on this website. Google uses their anonymous data about website visitors to serve them with advertisements that are more relevant to their interests.

You can opt out from Google Analytics and Google Analytics Advertising Features by turning off cookies in your browser. Please note, disabling cookies may result in reduced website functioning, not necessarily on Market Index but on a significant number of websites on the internet.

Visit the [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com.au/analytics/) page for more information or [opt-out here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

**Third Party Links**  
Market Index links to other websites via advertisements and external links. If the external websites have analytics software installed (almost every major website has analytics installed) then they will be able to see which website you have come from. Any linked external website should also have their own Privacy Policy and we have no control over their website or its content.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
Market Index reserves the right to make amendments to this Privacy Policy at any time. If you have objections to the Privacy Policy, you should not access or use the Site.

**Accessing Your Personal Information**  
You have a right to access your personal information, subject to exceptions allowed by law. If you would like to do so, please let us know. You may be required to put your request in writing for security reasons. Market Index reserves the right to charge a fee for searching for, and providing access to, your information on a per request basis.

**Contacting us**

Please contact Market Index if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy. Email: [info@marketindex.com.au](mailto:info@marketindex.com.au)
